[Previously on GinTama]
[After all that, the Benizakura Arc has come to an end. Thank you for your hard work, DOES-san.]
[Note: "Shura," the song just played, is performed by the band DOES]
[Starting from this episode, we'll be returning to the usual GinTama. Viewers tune in and get ready.]
(土方)ほぅ… 桂と高杉がね…｡
Katsura and Takasugi, eh?
(山崎)過激派だった桂の野郎も➡
Katsura used to be an extremist, but now he's a moderate.
今では
すっかり穏健派になりかわり➡
とかく暴走しがちな
攘夷浪士たちを抑える➡
In fact, he keeps the easily agitated Anti-Foreigner Faction from running amuck.
ﾌﾞﾚｰｷ役となっていると聞きます｡
ﾊﾞﾘﾊﾞﾘの武闘派である
高杉一派とぶつかり合うのは➡
It was only a matter of time before Katsura bumped heads with Takasugi and his more militant faction.
目に見えていました｡
Both sides suffered huge losses. There were over fifty dead and missing.
(山崎)両陣営とも
被害は甚大なもようで➡
死者 行方不明者 50数名｡
あの人斬り似蔵も行方不明とか｡
Nizo the Butcher's whereabouts are also unknown.
これで しばらく
ﾔﾂらも動けないでしょう｡
Both sides will be out of action for a while.
(土方)しかし 解せねえ｡
But I still don't get it.
岡田 河上ら猛者を擁する
高杉に比べ➡
Takasugi had Okada, Kawakami and other fierce fighters on his side, but Katsura didn't have anyone.
桂は ろくな手駒を
持っていなかったはず｡
いったい どうやって高杉たちと
互角に張り合ったってんだ？
How in the world did he manage to hold his own against Takasugi's group?
(山崎)それなんですがね
気になる情報が…｡
About that... I have some interesting information.
桂側に妙な連中が
助っ人についていたらしくて➡
It seems Katsura had a strange team of helpers. They were...
ｿｲﾂが 妙なｶﾞｷ２人を連れた
ﾊﾞｶ強い銀髪頭の 侍らしいんです｡
a ridiculously strong silver-haired samurai and two strange kids.
(山崎)副長！ ｺｲﾂはもしかして…｡
Vice-Chief, do you think that might've been...
(土方)野郎か…｡
Him?
たしか あの野郎は 以前➡
Seems that guy was involved with the Ikedaya incident with Katsura,
池田屋の件のときも
桂と関わってるふうだったが➡
うまいこと
逃げられたんだったな…｡
but he managed to get away.
(土方)洗うか…｡
副長！
Shall we check him out?
Vice-Chief...
もともと うさんくせえ野郎だ｡
He's always seemed a little fishy.
探れば
何か出てくるﾔﾂだっていうのは➡
You must've realized it, too.
お前も 前から わかってただろう｡
If we investigate, we might find a few skeletons in his closet.
派手な動きもせなんだから
捨て置いたが➡
He never did anything to attract attention, so I let him be, but...
潮時かもな｡
It might be time.
これで もし旦那が
攘夷活動に関わっていた場合は？
What if we find out he's involved with the Anti-Foreigner Faction?
んなもん決まってるだろう｡
That should be obvious.
穏健派だろうが過激派だろうが
ｵﾚたちの敵には違いねえ！
Whether he's a moderate or a radical, he's still our enemy.
斬れ！
Kill him.
["Even Mummy Hunters Sometimes Turn into Mummys"]
♪♪～
[Note: He's wearing a Seigaku uniform from Prince of Tennis]
[Note: He's wearing a Hyotei uniform from Prince of Tennis]
(山崎)ﾊｧ！
(武蔵)ﾌﾝ!!
(山崎)やぁ！
(武蔵)てや!!
♪♪～
ﾁｯ！
(山崎)もらった～！
Wah!  It's huge!!
(武蔵)うわぁ～ でかっ！
ぐぅ～…｡
えっ？
(爆発音)
まだまだだね｡
You're not there yet.
[Note: Ryoma's favorite phrase from Prince of Tennis]
(歓声)
はぁ…｡
Kill him...? The Vice-Chief's not being reasonable.
《しかし 斬れとは
副長も ﾑﾁｬを言う｡
自分も旦那に負けたくせに➡
He already lost to that guy, so how am I supposed to beat him?
ｵﾚが勝てるわけないだろう｡
なに考えてんだ…｡
What's he thinking...?
まっ とりあえず
何かやらないと怒られるし➡
I need to do something or he'll yell at me,
まずは
聞き込みでもやってみるか…》
so maybe I should start by asking around.
(隊士)山崎さん！ 危ない!!
Yamazaki-san, look out!
あっ…｡
Huh? The Odd jobs? Thunder Dome?
(お通)えっ？ 万事屋さんﾀﾞｰﾄﾞｰﾑ？
(山崎)
えっ… えぇ｡ 万事屋のこと➡
Th-That's right.
If you know anything about them, can you please tell me?
何か知ってたら
教えてくれないかと思いまして｡
Oh! That's no good!
あぁ ﾀﾞﾒﾀﾞﾒ!! ちゃんと
お通語で しゃべってくれないと➡
You have to talk in Otsu language or I won't cooperate. Intestine burst!
協力してあげ内臓破裂｡
じゃあ 何か教えてくれると
嬉しまんと川料理学園｡
If you've heard anything, I'd appreciate you letting me know. Shimantogawa Cooking Academy.
う～ん… 万事屋さんは
何ていうか頼りになって➡
Hmm... The Odd Jobs is, how should I put it, someone I can rely on;
何でもしてくれて…｡
someone who'll do anything. But I have to pay him, of course. Fatal blunt force trauma.
あっ もちろん お金 払わないと
ﾀﾞﾒだけ鈍器で撲殺！
いや 仕事じゃなくて➡
No, I wasn't asking about his work.
I want you to tell me a bit more about his private side. Death Note.
もっとﾌﾟﾗｲﾍﾞｰﾄなことを
教えてほしいんですﾉｰﾄ｡
えっ ﾌﾟﾗｲﾍﾞｰﾄ？
About his private side?
う～ん よくわからﾅｲｽﾐﾄﾞﾙ｡
Hmm... I don't really know. Middle-aged...
[Note: The person in the corner is from Mobile Suit Gundam.]
(長谷川)あぁ!? 坂田 銀時？
Huh? Gintoki Sakata?
(山崎)えぇ｡
万事屋の旦那のこと➡
Yes. I'd like you to tell me anything you know about the Odd Jobs boss.
何か知っていれば
教えてもらえないかと…｡
(山崎)
あっ よければ これ… どうぞ｡
Oh, please have one.
おっ ありがと！ 気が利くね!!
Thanks. That's considerate of you.
ﾌﾟﾊ～！ あぁ ｱｲﾂ…｡
Yeah him... Him, eh? He's, you know...
ｱｲﾂね… ｱｲﾂは あれだよ！
はっきり言って ﾏﾀﾞｵだ｡
Frankly, he's still a Madao.
[Note: MA-DA-O is an acronym for "MAttaku DAme na Otoko" which means a totally hopeless man]
ﾏﾀﾞｵ？
まぁ なんだ…｡
Madao?
You know, it has a lot of meanings, but in essence it means he's hopeless.
いろいろ意味はあるみてえだが
要するに ﾀﾞﾒ人間ってことよ｡
ｵﾚから言わせれば ｱｲﾂは
多少の見どころはあるんだけどな｡
If you ask me though, I think he's got something going for him.
でも 世間の人間から言わせれば
やっぱ あれだな…｡
But if you ask the people around him,
真っ昼間からﾌﾟﾗﾌﾟﾗ ﾊﾟﾁﾝｺするわ…｡
they'll say he loafs around, plays pachinko, and drinks.
《確かに 旦那は
ﾀﾞﾒっぽく見えることもあるが➡
The Odd Jobs boss does seem hopeless,
あれが すべてとは思えない｡
but I don't think that's all there is to him.
やはり もっと近い人間を探して
聞く必要がありそうだ…》
I think I need to find out and ask the people who are closer to him.
って 人の話 聞いてる？
(山崎)あっ えぇ｡
Are you listening?
Uh, yeah.
What sort of person is the boss of the Odd Jobs to you, Hasegawa-san?
(山崎)
じゃあ 長谷川さんにとって➡
万事屋の旦那って
どんな人ですかね？
そうさなぁ… まぁ ひと言じゃ
片づけられねえっていうか…｡
Well, let's see... Someone you can't describe in a nutshell.
あぁ そうですか｡ わかりました｡
人の話 聞いてる!?
I see. I understand.
Are you listening?!
♪♪～
It's no use...
《ﾀﾞﾒだ…｡
やっぱり 周りの証言からは➡
I can't understand him from what the people around him tell me.
よく わからないや…｡
Or rather, no one really understands him.
っていうか
誰一人 まともに わかってないし｡
しかし 万事屋の旦那ってのは➡
But...the more I investigate, the more mysterious the Odd Jobs boss becomes.
調べれば調べるほど
不思議な人だな…｡
やはり 自分の目で
確かめるしか なさそうだ…》
I guess I'll have to see for myself, after all.
'Zaki-san, look out!
(隊士)ｻﾞｷさん 危ない！
Boss!
(山崎)旦那～！ 万事屋の旦那～！
Odd Jobs Boss!
あれ？ いないのかな？
Huh? Not home?
勝手に 入っちゃいますよ～！
I'm letting myself in.
Huh?
(山崎)あれ？
旦那～！ 旦那～！
Boss?
Boss.
旦那！
Are you in here? Not here?
(山崎)ここか！ …いないな｡
You. What're you doing there?
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)お前 そこで なにしてる？
(山崎)いっ!?
N-No...I'm...
いや… ﾎﾞｸは…！
Somehow, I sense we're alike. Are you a thief?
何か 私と 同じにおいが するよ｡
泥棒か？
言っちゃったよ この人！
You said it. You just said you're a thief.
自分が 泥棒だって
言っちゃってるよ！
How dare you! I'm a former thief!
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)失礼な！ 元 泥棒だよ！
What's with the cocky attitude!
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)なんだよ お前！
生意気なんだよ！
Don't look at me with those condescending eyes!
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)人を 見下した目で
見んじゃねえよ!!
(山崎)なに それ!? 逆ｷﾞﾚ!?
(お登勢)どうしたんだい？ ｷｬｻﾘﾝ｡
What're you getting angry at me for?!
What's going on, Catherine?
あっ お登勢さん…｡
Oh, Otose-san.
Forgive me.
すみません｡ あの 旦那は？
Is the boss in? Is the boss of the Odd Jobs in? This is for...
万事屋の旦那は
いらっしゃらないんでしょうか？
あっ よかったら これ…｡
I'll take it!
もらってやるよ！
(お登勢/山崎)お前がかよ！
It's not for you!
銀時に 用があるって言ったね？
You said you wanted to see Gintoki?
He got hurt or something and is recuperating at Shinpachi's place.
野郎なら ｹｶﾞしたとかで
新八んちで 療養中だよ｡
…療養中？
Recuperating?
《志村 新八の家…
恒道館道場か…｡
Shinpachi Shimura's home... A broken down dojo...
めんどくさいけど
今夜 いっちょ 忍び込むか…》
It's a bother, but maybe I'll sneak in there tonight.
(隊士)ｻﾞｷさん やばい!!
くらうか!!
'Zaki-san! Look out!
Not this time!
Look Out!
(隊士)暴れ馬だ～!!
(隊士)捕まえろ～!!
Runaway horse!
Catch him!
♪♪～
This is the place.
ここか…｡
It's bigger than I expected.
(山崎)意外に 広いな…｡
《しかし いよいよ怪しい｡
But this is getting more suspicious.
Could those injuries have been from that incident...?
ｹｶﾞとは
例の一件で 負ったものでは…｡
だとしたら やっぱり…！》
If so, then...
((斬れ！))
Kill him!
Man, what does he want me to do?
《ったく どうしろってんだよ…｡
I don't feel safe... I want to go home.
あっ やべえ… 帰りてえ…》
Who's there?!
(神楽)何奴!?
《ﾊﾞﾚた!?》
Do they know?!
Oh, so it's you.
(神楽)おやおや お前さんですか｡
(神楽)ｸｯｸｯｸｯ…
来ると思っていましたよ｡
I thought you'd show up.
《なんてこった…｡
さすが 旦那だ｡
Holy cow. The boss is good-he saw though everything.
全部 お見通しってわけか！》
(神楽)ﾌｯ… 死んだ仲間の
敵討ちというわけですか ﾏｽｶｯﾄよ｡
Have you come to avenge your dead friends, Muscat?
Huh? Muscat?
《山崎:はっ？ ﾏｽｶｯﾄ？》
Are you talking about Marilyn? Prieza!
[Note: Spoof on Frieza from Dragonball.]
｢ﾏﾘﾘﾝのことかぁぁ～っ!!
ﾌﾟﾘｰｻﾞぁぁぁ～っ!!｣
｢ﾄﾞｶｰﾝ！ ﾋﾞｼﾊﾞｼ ﾋﾞｼ！ ｸﾞﾌｯ！｣
Dokaa. Bishi-bashi-bishi. Gufu. Dooon!
｢ﾄﾞｰﾝ！ ｶﾞﾗｶﾞﾗ ﾌﾞﾘﾌﾞﾘﾃﾝ ﾌﾞﾘ｣
Gara-gara buri-buri ten, buri.
Buri-buri bushaa. Gara-gara gara goshi-goshi.
(神楽)｢ﾌﾞﾘ ﾌﾞﾘ ﾌﾞｼｬｰ｡ ｶﾞﾗｶﾞﾗ ｶﾞﾗ｣
She's reading JUMP out loud... How tedious.
《｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣の朗読…｡
紛らわしいﾏﾈを…》
"Huh?" Goshi-goshi-goshi. Ack. "There's blood on you, again."
(神楽)｢あっ また 血ついてる｣
Hey, I'm completely lost. Give it to me-I'll read it myself.
(銀時)お～い｡
なんか わけわかんねえよ！
ちょ 貸せ｡ もう 自分で読むから｡
No. JUMP is too stimulating for someone who's injured.
(神楽)ﾀﾞﾒｱﾙ！
ｹｶﾞ人に ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟは刺激的すぎね｡
I'll read it to you.
(神楽)私が 読んであげるね｡
だったら もうちょっと➡
Then read it the right way, so I can understand what's going on.
状況が わかるように
読んでくれや！
I'll sneak underneath.
《とにかく 下に潜ろう》
(神楽)銀ちゃん向けのﾏﾝｶﾞは…｡
Okay. Wait a minute. Something for Gin-chan...
Ahem. Manaka-dono, please turn off the light.
(神楽)｢ｱﾊﾝ｡ 間中どの
電気を 消してくだされ｣
Ignoring Nishino's words, Manaka leapt atop her like a wild beast...
｢そんな 弐誌乃の言葉も
無視して➡
間中は おもむろに
弐誌乃に またがり➡
ｹﾀﾞﾓﾉの如く｣
だぁぁぁ～っ！ いい！
Never mind! That's enough! You're too young for this!
もう いいって！
早い！ お前には まだ…!!
(お妙)なに 勝手に
動いとんじゃ～!!
I told you not to move around!
(２人)ぎゃぁぁぁ～っ!!
(お妙)もう 銀さんったら
ﾎﾝﾄ 何度 言ったら わかるの？
Gin-san, how many times do I have to tell you before you understand?
If you move again with those injuries, you'll die. (I'll kill you.)
そんなｹｶﾞで動いたら 今度こそ…｡
死にますよ｡
((お妙:殺しますよ))
Sorry, but can I check into a hospital? I'm hearing things.
すみませんけど 病院に
入院させてもらえませんか？
幻聴が 聞こえるんだけど…｡
なんかね ｷﾐの声がね➡
I thought I heard an ominous echoing voice say, "I'll kill you."
ﾀﾞﾌﾞって 殺す～！ とか
聞こえるんだけど！
Ah! No! No! Don't get me wrong, it's not you, it's me.
いやいや いやいや！
ｷﾐが 悪いんじゃないんだよ！
ｵﾚが 悪いのさ～！
(お妙)ﾀﾞﾒですよ｡
You mustn't. If you checked into a hospital, you'd just sneak out.
(お妙)入院なんてしたら
どうせ すぐ 逃げ出すでしょう？
If you're here, I can easily hunt you down.
(お妙)ここなら
すぐ しとめられるもの～｡
ほら～！ 今も また 聞こえた！
There it is again! I thought I heard her say she'd hunt me down!
しとめるなんて ありえないもの！
言うわけないもの～!!
(新八)銀さ～ん
幻聴じゃありませんよ～｡
Gin-san, you're not hearing things.
《あっ… あぶねえ…｡
That was close! I was almost skewered.
串刺しに なるところだった…｡
But now I have a peephole. Now I can see inside the room.
しかし おかげで 覗き穴が…｡
これで 部屋の
様子が見てとれるぞ》
You must be getting hungry. I made you something to eat.
(お妙)そろそろ お腹が
減ったころ でしょう？
(お妙)お料理 作りましたよ｡
I made rice gruel with egg.
卵がゆを作ったんだけど どうぞ｡
でも 動けないから
食べさせてあげないとね｡
But since you can't move, I'll have to feed you.
これ… なんて拷問ですか？
What kind of torture is this?
《なんだ ﾒｼか？》
What? A meal?
姉御 私に やらして｡
Sis, let me feed him.
Sure, Kagura-chan, you can be his mother.
はいはい 神楽ちゃんは
お母さんねぇ… どうぞ｡
Here you go.
(神楽)あっ｡
《あぁっ！ 目にぃっ
目に 何か 刺さった!!
My eye!! Something's in my eye!!
焼けるぅっ！ 目が… 目がぁっ!!
It burns!! My eye...my eye!
劇物だ！ 間違いない!!
これは なんらかの兵器だ｡
It's some toxic substance! I'm positive! It's some kind of chemical weapon.
間違いないっ！ ｱｲﾂら
ｵﾚの存在に気づいてる!!
No doubt about it! They know I'm here!
早く逃げないと 殺され…》
If I don't quickly get away...
I'll be killed...
(お妙)向こうに 残りが
あるんで とってきますね｡
I have some more over there. I'll go get it.
I said, don't move!
動くなっつってんだろうが!!
(銀時/山崎)ｷﾞｬｱｱｱｱ！
She's got to be kidding! I won't survive a recuperation like this!
冗談じゃねえ！
こんな生活 身がもたねえ!!
待て こら 天ﾊﾟｰ!!
Get back here, you wavy-haired freak!
Shin-chan, turn on "Fort mode"!
新ちゃん！ 要塞ﾓｰﾄﾞ ｵﾝよ｡
は～い｡
All right.
♪♪～
(お妙)ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ…
逃げられると思うてか!?
You think you can escape?!
(お妙)この屋敷はな…
幾多のｽﾄｰｶｰ被害を受け➡
This mansion has had numerous stalker attacks.
賊の侵入を阻むため
ｺﾂｺﾂと 武装を重ね➡
So to keep the bad guys out, we've been diligently adding protective armaments.
もはや 要塞と呼べる
代物になってるんだよ｡
So now it's something of a fortress.
ﾈｽﾞﾐ１匹 逃げられや
しない 鋼の要塞にね!!
Not even a mouse can escape
from this iron fortress!
道場の復興は？
What happened to restoring the dojo?
♪♪～
[Chome Chome Chome Koh! Eat it!]
[Your Older Brother is Chome Chome Chome Chome Chome]
♪♪～
[Your Father is Chome Chome]
[Twelve songs including her debut single, "Your Mother is Chome Chome!"]
(お通)は～い 寺門 通だﾖｰﾄﾞﾁﾝｷ｡
This is Tsu Terakado! Iodine solution!
(お通)私の初 ｺﾝﾋﾟｱﾙﾊﾞﾑが
いよいよ 発売んきんたむし｡
My first compilation album is now on sale! Jock itch!
My producer, Tsunpo, loves how we keep selling the same sound. Big Magnum.
ﾌﾟﾛﾃﾞｭｰｻｰのつんぽさんも➡
同じ音源で 何回も商売
できるって大喜ﾋﾞｯｸﾞﾏｸﾞﾅﾑ｡
Tsu Terakado's compilation album:
"Forget Your Worldly Worries and Have Fun Today Necromancer" is on sale at last!
買わないと ﾎｸﾛ引きちぎるよ｡
If you don't buy it, I'll rip your mole off.
♪♪～
ｷﾞｬｰ!!
なにおっ!!
What?!
ぬわぁっ!!
♪♪～
Dammit! What's going on?
ﾁｸｼｮｰ どうなってんだよ！
どういう仕組みで 上から➡
How's it rigged to fall from above?! What's with this house?!
落ちてくんだよ…!?
なんなんだよ この家は！
There!
そこかぁ！
ﾁｯ… 逃げ足だけは 早えな｡
Tsk.
He's good at running away.
新ちゃん！ ｿﾙよ！ ｿﾙの出番よ!!
Shin-chan! The SOL! It's time for the SOL!
[Note: Spoof of SOL (Satellite in Orbital Laser-weapon) from the movie AKIRA.]
Okay, okay.
はい は～い｡
♪♪～
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
ﾌｩ… ここまで来れば… はい？
I should be safe out here...
Huh?
(山崎)うわぁっ!!
(爆発音)
Wh-Wha-What is that?
なんなんだ なんなんだよ ありゃ｡
(山崎)まさか そんな… まさか!?
It can't be...could it?!
[SOL 740 Stalker Punishing Laser]
新ちゃん！ あそこに集中砲火!!
Shin-chan! Concentrate fire on that location!
ふえ～い｡
Okay.
(山崎)えぇぇっ!!
♪♪～
(山崎)ｷﾞｬｰ!!
ﾌﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ… そうよ 新ちゃん｡
That's it, Shin-chan!
石器時代に 帰しておしまい!!
Send him back to the Stone Age!
いや 家 壊れるし…｡
No, that'll destroy the house.
It's the Chief! It's all the fault of that fool's stupid daily behavior.
局長かぁ！ あのﾊﾞｶの
日頃の行いのせいで!!
(近藤)ｱｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ…
お妙さん 甘いですよ｡
Otae-san, you missed something!
If there's absolutely no way out,
(近藤)絶対 出られないと
いうことは 裏を返せば➡
then the reverse of that means it becomes an impenetrable love nest for you and me!
お妙さんと ｵﾚの
絶対不可侵領域の➡
愛の巣が できるということ！
そうだ そういうことなんでしょ｡
That's right. That's what it means.
ﾎﾟｼﾞﾃｨﾌﾞだ… ﾎﾟｼﾞﾃｨﾌﾞな
ことだけ考えろ 勲！
Think positive. Think only positive thoughts, Isao.
If you think negative thoughts for even an instant, Isao,
この 状況で 一瞬でも
ﾈｶﾞﾃｨﾌﾞなことを考えてみろ 勲｡
あのﾊﾞｰｹﾞﾝﾀﾞｯｼｭの二の舞 勲！
you'll end up just like the Baagen-Dash!
(山崎)やっぱり いたんかい！
So you were here, just as I thought!
That voice! 'Zaki! That you, Yamazaki?!
(近藤)おっ その声は ｻﾞｷ 山崎か！
Of all people, the one who's like a death curse is the only one who can save me!
(近藤)よりによって 死の呪文
みたいなﾔﾂが助けにきやがった｡
(山崎)それじゃあ…
座男陸さん呼んできますね｡
Okay, I'll call Zaoriku-san for you.
I was kidding! Only kidding!
(近藤)ｳｿ！ ｳｿぴょ～ん!!
更木君でなくて よかった｡
I'm glad you weren't Zaraki-kun!
(近藤)剣八君でなくて
よかった 勲 ねっ…｡
I'm glad you were not Kenpachi-kun!
Let's get out of here quickly!
(近藤)早く引き上げて！ ﾔﾊﾞｯ!!
Uh-oh, my hands and feet are getting shaky...like a newborn gorilla...
もう手足が ｶﾞｸｶﾞｸで
生まれたてのｺﾞﾘﾗ…｡
You mean like a newborn colt, Chief.
(山崎)子馬です 局長｡
(近藤)違う 違う！
No, no! I wasn't mistaken.
(近藤)今の間違ってないからね…
ｵﾚが言ってんのは➡
I was referring to my mental state.
精神的な意味だから 誰だって
生まれたては 不安じゃ～ん！
Every creature is a bit unsteady when it's first born!
ｱﾝﾀは 生まれて 30年近く
たってんのに不安定ですよ｡
You're still unsteady even thirty years after you were born.
(さっちゃん)ﾌﾌｯ… 甘いわね｡
You're too soft.
Did you really think a trap like this was going to break my feelings for Gin-san?
こんな罠で
私の銀さんへの想いが➡
折れるとでも思った？ お妙さん｡
Did you, Otae-san?
裏を返せば これは あなたが
私を恐れてるってことでしょう？
Looking at it from the flip side, this means you fear me, doesn't it?
You think I'll take Gin-san away from you, don't you?
銀さんをとられるかも って
思っているわけでしょう？
That's it. That's what it means.
そうよ そういうことよ｡
Think positive. Think only positive thoughts, Sachan.
ﾎﾟｼﾞﾃｨﾌﾞよ ﾎﾟｼﾞﾃｨﾌﾞなことだけ
考えるのよ さっちゃん｡
If you think negative thoughts for even an instant,
この状況で一瞬でもﾈｶﾞﾃｨﾌﾞなこと
考えてみな さっちゃん➡
Sachan, you'll end up just like your glasses.
あのﾒｶﾞﾈの二の舞さっちゃん！
There's another idiot here!
(山崎)ここにも ﾊﾞｶがいたよ!!
That voice is Gin-san's!
(さっちゃん)その声は銀さん！
助けにきてくれたのね｡
He's come to rescue me!
あぁ ごめんなさい 私 銀さんを➡
I'm so sorry... I snuck in here so I could care for you, but I ended up like this.
看病しようと忍び込んだら
こんなことに…｡
(山崎)違えよﾊﾞｶ！ ﾒｶﾞﾈ取れたら
耳まで遠くなるのか!?
Wrong guy, stupid! Does losing your glasses affect your hearing, too?!
(さっちゃん)
ああっ やっぱり銀さん！
It is you, Gin-san! That sadistic touch is uniquely yours.
私を喜ばせる そのｻﾄﾞっぷりは
銀さんだけだもの➡
私は だまされないぞ～！
You can't fool me!
What?!
(山崎)なんだ!?
この落とし穴に落ちるﾊﾞｶは➡
Were these pits specifically designed to catch obsessed freaks?
人を腹立たせる ﾊﾞｶばっかりか!?
Hey, Death Spell!! What're you doing?!
(近藤)こら死の呪文 何してんだ！
If you don't hurry, this newborn gorilla is gonna be new-dead!
早くしないと 生まれたての
ｺﾞﾘﾗが…｡
うるせえ！
Shut up!
It is you, Gin-san!
(さっちゃん)やっぱり銀さんだわ｡
そうやって➡
You're having fun by making me impatient, aren't you?
じらして楽しんでるのね！
いいわよ➡
Okay, I'll go along!
のってあげるわよ！
(山崎)お前も黙れ!!
You shut up, too!
What?!
なにぃ!?
万事屋の野郎が １つ屋根の下➡
You mean that Odd Jobs bastard is sleeping under the same roof as Otae-san?!
お妙さんと一緒に
寝泊まりしているだと!?
どこに食いついてるんですか？
What're you getting at?
Remember the investigation! You sent me to investigate the Odd Jobs boss!
調査！
万事屋の旦那を調査しにきたの！
Don't give me that!
ふざけんなよ！
そんなさぁ だってさ ずるいよ!!
That's...I mean...not fair!
ｵﾚなんてさ
何回もｱﾀｯｸしてるのにさ➡
I've tried so many times to approach her,
竹槍ﾙｰﾑで寝てる的なさぁ もう｡
but I never get closer than a room full of bamboo stakes.
This is hopeless. He's not listening at all.
ﾀﾞﾒだよ これ｡ 全然 聞いてないよ｡
What? You're losing heart just because of that?
なに あなた
そんなことでﾍｺんでるの？
ｽﾄｰｶｰの風上にもおけない人ね｡
なんだぁ ｸｿｱﾏ!!
You're an embarrassment to stalkers.
What was that, bitch?!
おいおい なんか
ｽﾄｰｶｰ談議になっちゃってるよ｡
Hey, hey, it's beginning to sound like a stalkers' roundtable.
この世界に その人が➡
You should appreciate the fact that a person like her even exists.
存在することだけで
感謝しなさいよ｡
少し ﾏｿﾞっ気が
足りないんじゃなくて？
Maybe you're lacking the masochistic feeling.
私なんて銀さんが 子供がいるって
聞いたときも 平気だったわ｡
When I heard Gin-san had a kid, I was fine with it.
In fact, it turned me on.
むしろ興奮したわよ｡
You've been calling me a stalker all this time,
さっきから人を ｽﾄｰｶｰ ｽﾄｰｶｰと➡
ｱﾝﾀと一緒にしないでくれるか？
but don't lump me together with you!
I'm just persistent, insidious and clumsier at love than most.
ｵﾚはね 人より恋愛のしかたが
不器用で しつこくて➡
That's all it is!
陰湿なだけだ!!
それが ｽﾄｰｶｰです｡
That's a stalker.
(さっちゃん)お笑いね！
That's funny.
You won't even admit you're a stalker.
自分が ｽﾄｰｶｰということも
気づいてないんだ!?
I tell you, I am absolutely not a stalker!
(近藤)断じて
ｽﾄｰｶｰじゃありません！
If anything, I'm a hunter...of love.
強いて言うならﾊﾝﾀｰです 愛の｡
That's enough, hunter. This is no time for a confession.
(山崎)ﾊﾝﾀｰ もういいでしょう｡
そんなこと言ってる
場合じゃないんですって｡
Depending on the circumstances, I have orders to kill.
場合によっちゃ斬れ って
そういう指令が下ってるんです｡
どうすりゃいいんですかね？
What should I do?
Why not kill? Shall I do it for you?
斬ればいいじゃん そんなん！
なんなら ｵﾚがやってやろうか!!
Go ahead and try.
やってみなさいよ｡
You know what'll happen to you if you lay a hand on Gin-san, don't you?
銀さんに手を出したら どうなるか
わかってるんでしょうね!?
おいおいおい
ちょっと２人とも やめ…｡
Hey, hey!
Just a minute! Stop that, you two...
ﾋ-ｺﾗ ﾊﾞﾋﾝﾊﾞﾋﾝ…｡
ったく まいったぜ
なんで こんな目に…｡
Good grief... Why does this happen to me...?
Kill!!
(山崎)あっ！
Gintoki!
銀時～!!
(さっちゃん)させるか～っ!!
No you don't!
(２人)うぉ～！
Found you!
(お妙)見～つけた!!
(神楽)天ﾊﾟｰ！
(みんな)うぉ～！
うわわわ…！
わ～っ！
《山崎:副長…｡
Vice-Chief...
That man isn't a person someone like me can comprehend.
あの旦那は どうにも➡
ｵﾚごときが
推し量れる人じゃないようで…｡
なんだか
つかみどころがなくてね｡
He seems to be a strange sort. I can't tell if he's loved or despised.
愛されてんだか憎まれてんだか…｡
周りを騒ぎに巻き込むくせに
人が集まってくるようで…｡
He gets people caught up in his troubles,
but people are attracted to him.
えっ そんなこと聞いてないって？
What? You haven't heard?
Is he an Anti-Foreigner loyalist?
攘夷志士？
Well...I couldn't really tell.
いや… あんまり…
わからなかったんですけど｡
でもね…》
But...
(鉄子)あの…｡
Excuse me...
Excuse me. Is Gin-san here?
す… すみません…｡
あの… 銀さん いますか？
はっ？
ここのｳﾁの人ですよね？
Huh?
You live here, right?
ここに銀さんがいるって
聞いてきたんだけど➡
I heard that Gin-san was here. I couldn't open the gate, so...
開かなくて｡
あぁ…
今は入らないほうがいいよ➡
I don't think you should go in there right now. It's dangerous. 'Bye.
危ないから｡ じゃ…｡
Then...
(鉄子)あの…
じゃあ せめて ことづてを｡
Can I at least leave a message?
Tell him...a lot has happened to me, but I'm fine now.
(鉄子)私… いろいろあったけど➡
今は元気にやってます｡
本当にありがとう って｡
Tell him...I'm truly grateful.
♪♪～
He probably doesn't even think about the Anti-Foreigner Faction's activities or politics like that.
《山崎:攘夷活動だなんだ➡
そんな難しいことは
あの人は考えとらんでしょう…｡
あの人は きっと…》
I'm sure he just wanted...
to see that girl's smiling face. That's how I feel. Sagaru Yamazaki.
作文!?
A composition?!
What's this? I'm in worse shape than I was before.
[Preview]
If samurai are dogs, then ninja are cats.
They'll cuddle up to anyone who has food.
There's no beauty or ugliness in the way we live.
The next episode... "The Preview Section in JUMP is Always Unreliable."
[Okuni the Clairvoyant possesses eyes that can see the future.]
[Former Oniwabanshu agent, Zenzo Hattori, now works part-time at a pizza joint.]
(ルナ)宇宙開発が さかんな時代｡
ｽﾍﾟｰｽｺﾛﾆｰで➡
何不自由なく 暮らしていた
私たち７人と １ぴきは➡
修学旅行に出発した その日に
宇宙のあらしにあい…｡
(重力あらしの音)
見知らぬ わく星に 流れ着いた｡
そして
私たちの ｻｳﾞｧｲｳﾞｧﾙが始まった｡